Guide to the Burnham Kelly papers, 1947-1971
Kelly, Burnham papers, 1947-1971
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Burnham Kelly papers, 1947-1971
15-1-1633
Burnham Kelly.
9.8 cubic ft.
Correspondence, manuscripts, reports, bibliographic cards, speeches, lesson plans, a consulting project, and subject files.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, manuscripts, and reports relating to the development of an architecture and regional planning program at the University of Puerto Rico and to Kelly's visit to observe the planning and architecture programs at the University Del Valle in Colombia; file on the planning of a Cornell art museum, 1959-1968; report of the Centennial Planning Committee, 1960-1961, including material on the size of the University. Also, bibliographic cards on construction techniques. Additional records include speeches, lesson plans, consulting project and subject files, concerning Burnham Kelly's career as Dean of the College of Architecture, Art and Planning, 1960-1971.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Burnham Kelly was Dean of the College of Architecture, Art and Planning, 1960-1971.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, manuscripts, and reports relating to the development of an architecture and regional planning program at the University of Puerto Rico and to Kelly's visit to observe the planning and architecture programs at the University Del Valle in Colombia; file on the planning of a Cornell art museum, 1959-1968; report of the Centennial Planning Committee, 1960-1961, including material on the size of the University. Also, bibliographic cards on construction techniques.
Additional records include speeches, lesson plans, consulting project and subject files, concerning Burnham Kelly's career as Dean of the College of Architecture, Art and Planning, 1960-1971.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kelly, Burnham.; Cornell University. College of Architecture, Art, and Planning.; University of Puerto Rico.; Universidad del Valle.; Cornell University. College of Architecture, Art, and Planning--Administration.
Subjects:
Universities and colleges--Administration.; Architecture--Study and teaching.; City planning--Study and teaching.; Regional planning--Study and teaching.; Art museums--New York (State)--Ithaca.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Universidad del Valle, Colombia: Planning and architecture programs
  - La Comunidad de Siloe, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Los Andes, Cali, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Los Andes, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Colombia ie. Cali, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Colombia, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Rockefeller trip--Cali, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cali, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Estudios de Graduados en Planification, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Series II. University of Puerto Rico: Development of architecture and regional planning programs
  - Benitez, 1947, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Architectural planning, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Architectural planning, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Benitez, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Proposal Escuela de Arquitectura de la Universidad de Puerto Rico (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Puerto Rico, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Graduate Program in Planning, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Puerto Rico, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Puerto Rico, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Series III. Construction Techniques
  - Bibliographic cards re: construction techniques (index file box) (Box 2)
- Series IV. Cornell University
  - Report of the Centennial Planning Committee, 1960-1961 (Box 3)
- Series V. Miscellaneous
  - class notes, speeches, consulting and subject files (Box 4-11)
- Series VI. Publications
  - Publications by B. K. (Box 12)
- Series VII. American Institute of Planners (AIP)
  - AIP Committee: Defense considerations in AIP (Box 13)
  - AIP Committee: Urban Vulnerability (Box 13)